<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="axedrax.ga/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="axedrax.ga/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-03-20T01:04:30+00:00</updated><id>axedrax.ga/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Axe Drax</title><subtitle>The collective that oppose the company Drax. We are direct action groups, local campaigns and individuals.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Drax Expand Logging into Canadian Ancient Woodland</title><link href="axedrax.ga/2021/03/19/pinnicle-pellets/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Drax Expand Logging into Canadian Ancient Woodland" /><published>2021-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>axedrax.ga/2021/03/19/pinnicle-pellets</id><content type="html" xml:base="axedrax.ga/2021/03/19/pinnicle-pellets/">&lt;p&gt;Drax Plc plan to buy further into the wood burning industry, by purchasing
Pinnacle “Renewable Energy”. This company log some of the last remaining old
growth forests in British Columbia, to be burned at Drax Power Station in
North Yorkshire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They will be voting on this a the end of March, and remote votes must be in by
29th March. This is a surprise as Drax plan to have their Annual General
meeting on 21st April.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stand.earth/latest/forest-conservation/forests-and-wood-pellets/drax-dont-burn-canada%E2%80%99s-old-growth-forests&quot;&gt;this summary article&lt;/a&gt; by Canadian organisation Stand.Earth. Stand.Earth
have also launched a full investigation into British Columbia’s which can be read
in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stand.earth/sites/stand/files/report-canada-wood-pellet-industry.pdf&quot;&gt;this document&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a quote taken from the above article:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;UK residents may be shocked to learn that their power is being generated
  by burning some of the last stands of old and natural forests in British
  Columbia, home to endangered wildlife like caribou and among the most
  carbon-rich in the world—right up until they are clearcut to make wood
  pellets.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In no world is this acceptable, and to be growing this sector during a
  global climate crisis is horrifying. Old growth forests in BC are nearly
  gone, and the provincial government campaigned on a commitment to protect
  old forests while pursuing a paradigm shift for forestry. We were promised
  a new future for forests, but allowing them instead to be clearcut and
  shipped overseas to be burned in coal converted plants is medieval.
  People living in the UK and Canada must come together to oppose this
  industry and support real, clean renewable energy that protects forests
  and our climate.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tegan Hansen, Forest Campaigner, Stand.earth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &lt;strong&gt;cannot go unanswered in the UK&lt;/strong&gt;, and we must take the short time
we have to do everything we can to stop Drax committing this climate
crime. We must remember that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biofuelwatch.org.uk/axedrax-campaign/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;the UK Government fund Drax&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and that
any crime Drax commit the Government are complicit in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We must come together and take action. Watch this space for suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Areas we need help in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Managing our social media&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Writing press releases&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Affinity groups prepared to take action independently&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People who can make info-graphics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact us on &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:axedrax@pm.me&quot;&gt;axedrax [at] pm.me&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to
get involved in organising against Drax. Any amount of help is appreciated. You
also just &lt;a href=&quot;https://axedrax.ga/signup/&quot;&gt;sign up&lt;/a&gt; for updates about taking action.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">On 31st March, Drax shareholders will vote on acquiring the wood pellet production company Pinnacle Pellets. This will mean ancient forests burned in UK power station.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="axedrax.ga/assets/images/viewsfromabove.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="axedrax.ga/assets/images/viewsfromabove.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">End the Train of Destruction</title><link href="axedrax.ga/2020/08/10/etd/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="End the Train of Destruction" /><published>2020-08-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-08-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>axedrax.ga/2020/08/10/etd</id><content type="html" xml:base="axedrax.ga/2020/08/10/etd/">&lt;p&gt;
  The Axe Drax group, a coalition between Biofuelwatch, Extinction
  Rebellion and Save Rimrose Valley are taking action on the 14th
  of August against Drax Power Station, the UK’s biggest polluter.
  Campaigners will stage creative and peaceful protests at 11 locations
  along the Drax train line which transports wood pellets from Liverpool
  Port to Drax Power Station. Alongside this there will be digital and
  social media actions. These actions are calling for an end to Drax’s
  tree burning and its train of destruction that carves a path through
  the North. Actions will range from banner drops to family-friendly
  puppet shows and tree planting. Campaigners will also call on MPs
  to transfer around £1 billion in UK renewable subsidies from biomass
  burning power stations like Drax to genuine renewables.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The Axe Drax protestors have three demands:
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Stop Subsidising Ecocide: the government must remove the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biofuelwatch.org.uk/axedrax-campaign/#C3&quot;&gt;
        £789.5 million in subsidies
      &lt;/a&gt; for Drax Power Station and transfer
      them to genuine renewables.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Leave it in the Ground: stop Drax building Europe’s biggest ever
      fossil gas power station.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Stop the Lies: end what is possibly the most comprehensive and
      dangerous greenwashing campaign the UK has seen.
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Twelve times a day the Drax trains cross the viaduct in the centre of our
    little West Yorkshire town of Todmorden. They're really long, usually 25
    wagons,  and they really do draw your eye. The slogans on all the wagons
    look really progressive 'Biofuels-powering the future’ and 'Pioneering the
    northern powerhouse'. It’s only because I campaigned in the past over Drax's
    coal burning emissions that I decided to investigate their claims for myself.
    I found out they were greenwashing these claims and were not only causing
    massive environmental damage but huge social harm too.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;cite&gt;Maggie Smith from Todmorden&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Drax Power Station, located in Yorkshire, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biofuelwatch.org.uk/axedrax-campaign/#easy-footnote-1-9267&quot;&gt;
    burns 12 million tonnes of trees
    every year
  &lt;/a&gt;. Despite being legally classified as ‘renewable’
  by the UK government, it remains the largest carbon emitter in the
  UK. This takes advantage of a carbon accounting loophole,
  meaning that they are able to exclude the carbon cost of clear
  felling forests in the US when they are burned in the UK. In 2019
  Drax emitted almost 13 million tonnes of CO₂ from burning wood, and
  received £2.36 million in daily subsidy with £2.16 million counted
  as renewable subsidies. This is a grave misuse of public money,
  and Axe Drax are calling for an end to all subsidies for Drax and for
  them to be transferred towards funding genuine renewable energy projects.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  We are taking action, not only because of the environmental damage
  caused but the immediate and destructive impact Drax has upon human
  lives. Supposed bioenergy solutions often have the same fatal flaws
  associated with fossil fuels, they hurt low income BIPOC communities the
  most and serve to perpetuate environmental racism.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  In the Southern US, communities living in close proximity to the
  wood pellet mills used to supply Drax suffer from
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dogwoodalliance.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Community-Voices-Fact-Sheet.pdf&quot;&gt;
  air, water and noise pollution
  &lt;/a&gt; as well as
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dogwoodalliance.org/2020/06/the-injustice-of-bioenergy-production/&quot;&gt;
  poverty and injustice
  &lt;/a&gt;. The
  destruction of forests caused by Drax also destroys
  biodiverse forests which local communities depend on for
  clean air and water. These forests have historically
  served to protect communities from extreme weather and flooding:
  only set to increase in the near future due to climate breakdown.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;cite&gt;Belinda Joyner, Dogwood Alliance Campaigner&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;q cite=&quot;https://www.dogwoodalliance.org/2020/06/the-injustice-of-bioenergy-production/&quot;&gt;
    Enviva has made people prisoners in their own homes. People are profitting and we’re suffering
  &lt;/q&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Harm brought upon communities by Drax occurs closer to home too,
  following the train line of destruction through the North.
  The extreme amount of wood pellets imported through Liverpool
  Peel Ports by Drax has forced the port to expand. This has created
  large amounts of noise pollution and disruption upon local communities -
  all so that Drax can continue slashing down ancient woodlands and pumping
  pollution into our air. Noise pollution follows the train line, harming
  communities in Calderdale all the way along to Selby which suffers from
  the constant pumping of pollution into the air.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Despite their constant greenwashing Drax continues to demonstrate a
  complete disregard for people's health, let alone the planet.
  In Selby, local air pollution levels are not measured - making it
  impossible for us to know exactly how much Drax is harming the health
  of local communities - despite the fact that York and the surrounding
  area have robust measuring systems in place. We know that
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pfpi.net/air-pollution-2&quot;&gt;burning wood
  pellets emits a large amount of air pollution&lt;/a&gt;, yet Drax fails to take
  responsibility for this.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    The practice of chopping down healthy trees to make pellets
    in the USA and importing these to the UK to be burned is just
    about as unsustainable as it gets.  Sadly, the Port of Liverpool
    is facilitating this.  With no hint of irony its owners, Peel
    Ports, bemoan the absence of East-West rail links for the
    movement of freight, but are more than happy to occupy a
    vital East-West link specifically for Drax, which could
    and should be being used to move containers.  Instead,
    Peel Ports are sitting back and waiting for the
    Government to build them a road for their HGVs, through a
    vital country park, destroying more trees in the process.
    This is what we're fighting and it's one of the reasons the
    Save Rimrose Valley campaign supports the calls Axe Drax.
    Big business literally bulldoze their way through our green
    spaces, harming the environment and impacting people's lives.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;It has to stop.&lt;/strong&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;cite&gt;Ms Kate Elder Fuller, Save Rimrose Valley campaigner&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The push for biofuels as a renewable solution is only increasing as we
  hurt towards climate and ecological collapse. AxeDrax has come together
  to demand that we listen to the science which demonstrates biofuels are
  not a viable solution. We demand that our government invests money in
  genuine renewables, that prioritise the well-being of communities and our
  planet over profit.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Notes for editors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biofuelwatch.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/drax-briefing-update-2020_compressed.pdf&quot;&gt;
      Biofuelwatch’s briefing on Drax
    &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dogwoodalliance.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Community-Voices-Fact-Sheet.pdf&quot;&gt;
      Dogwood Alliance - Community Voices Fact Sheet
    &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dogwoodalliance.org/2020/06/the-injustice-of-bioenergy-production/&quot;&gt;
      The Injustice of Bioenergy Production
    &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pfpi.net/air-pollution-2&quot;&gt;
      Biomass and air pollution
    &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biofuelwatch.org.uk/axedrax-campaign/#C3&quot;&gt;
      Drax subsidies
    &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Coronavirus&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Though we must take action, we must do so safely. Each of those taking
  action in person will be maintaining social distancing as far as
  possible, and will be wearing PPE with hand sanitizer available.
  We have provided safety guidelines to each group taking part in this
  action about following public health advice - as with climate change
  we aim to listen to the experts.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  We feel a duty to to balance the needs of people’s safety with the
  necessity of holding Drax accountable due to their greenwashing and
  ecologically destructive behaviour that destroys forests and livelihoods
  here in the North and in America. We are constantly making these decisions,
  and all are able to be changed if the situation regarding COVID-19 changes.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Climate campaigners will take part in peaceful and creative actions along the Liverpool-Selby train line to denounce the UKs biggest carbon emitter, Drax Power Station</summary></entry></feed>