<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-11-03T17:32:59+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Axe Drax</title><subtitle>The collective that oppose the company Drax. We are direct action groups, local campaigns and individuals.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Banner Drop</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/action/banner-drop/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Banner Drop" /><published>2021-03-29T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-03-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/action/banner-drop</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/action/banner-drop/">&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make a banner, see &lt;a href=&quot;/images&quot;&gt;our photo bank&lt;/a&gt; for idea&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find a location in your town/city that has good foot fall (e.g. over a bridge)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find someone to take photos&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drop the banner&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Share the photos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;section&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;signs&quot;&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&quot;sign&quot;&gt;
    Forests are friends not fuel
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&quot;sign&quot;&gt;
    Cut carbon not forests
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&quot;sign&quot;&gt;
    Axe Drax
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&quot;sign&quot;&gt;
    Love Trees #AxeDrax
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&quot;sign&quot;&gt;
    Don't feed Draxular
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&quot;sign&quot;&gt;
    Drax Biofuel Scam
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&quot;sign&quot;&gt;
    Love Wildlife #AxeDrax
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&quot;sign&quot;&gt;
    £789.5m a year for burning trees. Corruption??
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;/section&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="action" /><summary type="html">Make a banner, see our photo bank for idea Find a location in your town/city that has good foot fall (e.g. over a bridge) Find someone to take photos Drop the banner Share the photos Forests are friends not fuel Cut carbon not forests Axe Drax Love Trees #AxeDrax Don't feed Draxular Drax Biofuel Scam Love Wildlife #AxeDrax £789.5m a year for burning trees. Corruption??</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/photos/etd_drax.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/photos/etd_drax.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Paint the Streets</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/action/paint-the-streets/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Paint the Streets" /><published>2021-03-29T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-03-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/action/paint-the-streets</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/action/paint-the-streets/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;example-signs&quot;&gt;Example signs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;section&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;signs&quot;&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&quot;sign&quot;&gt;
    Forests are friends not fuel
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&quot;sign&quot;&gt;
    Cut carbon not forests
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&quot;sign&quot;&gt;
    Axe Drax
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&quot;sign&quot;&gt;
    Love Trees #AxeDrax
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&quot;sign&quot;&gt;
    Don't feed Draxular
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&quot;sign&quot;&gt;
    Drax Biofuel Scam
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&quot;sign&quot;&gt;
    Love Wildlife #AxeDrax
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
  &lt;div class=&quot;sign&quot;&gt;
    £789.5m a year for burning trees. Corruption??
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;/section&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="action" /><summary type="html">Example signs</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/photos/etd_drax.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/photos/etd_drax.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Phone banking</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/action/phone-banking/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Phone banking" /><published>2021-03-29T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-03-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/action/phone-banking</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/action/phone-banking/">&lt;p&gt;This action was planned a few times through the summer of 2020, this is a
summary of the information that was prepared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;be-kind&quot;&gt;Be kind&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People taking part in remote actions are asked to treat the people on the phone or over email and social media with respect. Please do not harass or threaten anyone over the phone during this action, as this is not necessary and can put you at risk of charge. Our job is to educate people on the harm of large scale biomass projects. Making calls to be annoying is not helpful for the following numbers, as you will most likely just be talking to a secretary or possibly a call centre worker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If however, you manage to in contact with anyone who actually has power be as
annoying as you like!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;briefing&quot;&gt;Briefing&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For each contact, there is a main script, a nuance document and a left message.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Main Script&lt;/strong&gt;: skeleton guidance for your call. From “hello” through to ending the conversation.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nuance document&lt;/strong&gt;: Link to key information about the campaign and Drax facts. Divided thematically.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Left message&lt;/strong&gt;: Suggested voicemail message to leave contacts who don’t answer your call.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Follow up with an email.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Make sure to BCC &lt;a href=&quot;mailto;axedrax@pm.me&quot;&gt;axedrax@pm.me&lt;/a&gt;, so in theory we
  can predict responses in future - or center actions around them.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tips-do&quot;&gt;Tips. DO…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DO know the script&lt;/strong&gt;: familiarise yourself with the content and flow. Read it out to yourself. You can even try as a role play with someone you trust (this could be a friend or a member of your local XR group/organisation). This is a way to build confidence before the action :)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DO strive for connection&lt;/strong&gt;: Try to imagine they’re sitting across from you. Ask questions and try to create a natural “back and forth”. The better you know the script, the easier this will be.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DO refer to #AxeDrax and affiliated groups in the third person&lt;/strong&gt;: People are more likely to be persuaded by the aims and purpose of the action/campaign, rather than by a stranger telling them how to feel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tips-dont-&quot;&gt;Tips. DON’T …&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DON’T worry if you go off script&lt;/strong&gt;: in fact we encourage riffing on it. However, there are a few pitfalls to avoid such as…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DON’T make assumptions&lt;/strong&gt; about their age, race, gender, or their attitudes about Drax.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DON’T debate or argue&lt;/strong&gt;: our task is to educate and not to annoy or anger anybody. If someone is genuinely asking questions, do your best to answer them. However, if someone is clearly disagreeing with you and trying to argue or debate, don’t engage. It’s always OK to say, “I have a lot of calls left to make today so I do have to go. Thanks for your time”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;phone-numbers-to-call&quot;&gt;Phone numbers to call&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your local MP:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://members.parliament.uk/member/&quot;&gt;find their details here&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Phone them up, expressing your genuine concern about the effects of Drax Power Station on pollution, wildlife and communities.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Ask them to:
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Write to the BEIS (Department for Business, Energy &amp;amp; Industrial Strategy) ministers Alok Sharma and Kwasi Karteng with their concerns about biofuel subsidies&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Ask parliamentary questions about biofuel subsidies&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Request a parliamentary debate around the issue&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Follow up your call with an email. You can use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cutcarbonnotforests.org/email-your-mp/&quot;&gt;Cut Carbon Not Forests email tool&lt;/a&gt;, and edit the example as is relevant. Remember to BCC &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:axedrax@pm.me&quot;&gt;axedrax@pm.me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alok Sharma&lt;/strong&gt;, Secretary of State for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy (BEIS).
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Department of BEIS makes decisions on where renewable subsidies go, they have the power to Axe Drax. Ask them to:&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Phone constituency address: &lt;a href=&quot;tel:01189413803&quot;&gt;0118 941 3803&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;If you are a constituent of Reading West, then please use this number.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;London office address: &lt;a href=&quot;tel:02072197131&quot;&gt;020 7219 7131&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;For anyone who is not a constituent of his.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Email, if you would be more comfortable with that: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:alok.sharma.mp@parliament.uk&quot;&gt;alok.sharma.mp@parliament.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ed Miliband&lt;/strong&gt;, Shadow Secretary of State for Business, Energy and Industrial Strategy.​​​​​
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Phone: &lt;a href=&quot;tel:02072197318&quot;&gt;020 7219 7318&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Email: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ed.miliband.mp@parliament.uk&quot;&gt;ed.miliband.mp@parliament.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;MP for Doncaster North so having a local address to hand would be useful. MPs are more likely to talk to you if you live in the local area.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Here is an example postcode: DN5 9PH&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Continue the call as the concerned constituent you are&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Salford City Council&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Buys energy from Haven Power (Drax Owned Energy Supplier) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.climateemergency.uk/blog/salford/&quot;&gt;has declared a climate emergency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;tel:01616076987&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0161 607 6987&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Salford council procurement, direct line&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;You can also &lt;a href=&quot;https://contactus.salford.gov.uk/?formtype=CCC&quot;&gt;contact them online here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yeo Valley&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Yeo Valley is a high profile customer of Haven Power, owned by Drax.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;tel:01761462798&quot;&gt;01761 462 798&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hello@yeovalley.co.uk&quot;&gt;hello@yeovalley.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Please ask Yeo Valley to follow through on its environmental commitments by switching from Haven Power to a clean energy supplier.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;-scripts&quot;&gt;📜 Scripts&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;-for-your-local-mp-and-ed-milliband&quot;&gt;🧐 For your local MP and Ed Milliband&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://members.parliament.uk/member/&quot;&gt;Find their details here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;left-message&quot;&gt;Left message&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good morning/afternoon. This is _____ and I am a constituent of _____. I’m reaching out to you to discuss the harmful effect Drax Power Station’s tree burning is having on communities in the UK, in the hopes that you can help to reduce biomass subsidies by writing to Alok Sharma and Kwasi Karteng. If you’d like to hear about this please return my call on [Number] before 5pm today. Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;main-script&quot;&gt;Main script&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Good morning/Good afternoon, is &lt;strong&gt;[YOUR MP]&lt;/strong&gt; available?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hello _______ . This is _______ calling on behalf of the #AxeDrax campaign. I am a constituent of &lt;strong&gt;[YOUR CONSTITUENCY]&lt;/strong&gt;. I’m phoning because I am very concerned about the climate crisis and I am particularly worried about Drax Power Station’s fossil fuel and tree burning. Are you aware that Drax Power Station is the greatest emitter of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; in the UK?
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(IF NO)&lt;/strong&gt; OK. Although Drax is phasing out coal, their power stations are being converted into biomass plants, with the false claims that this is renewable energy, when in truth burning trees for energy contributes more CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to the atmosphere than coal per unit of electricity produced. &lt;em&gt;Continue to 3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(IF YES)&lt;/strong&gt; That’s good to know that you are aware that the biomass industry isn’t as clean as Drax claims. &lt;em&gt;Continue to 3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Would you be willing to hear more about how Drax is harming communities in the UK?
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(IF NO)&lt;/strong&gt; No problem. I think it’s really important that we remove Drax’s biofuel subsidies, and redirect those towards truly renewable sources of energy, such as solar and wind, instead of using them to transport wood pellets across the planet. It would be great if you could write to the BEIS ministers Alok Sharma and Kwasi Karteng, ask Parliamentary Questions about biofuel subsidies, and perhaps request a parliamentary debate around the issue.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(IF YES)&lt;/strong&gt; Great. You might already know that the beginning of Drax’s biomass production is in the Southern USA, where large areas of forests are torn down and pelletised in factories. This process harms the communities because it takes away nature and increases pollution, ultimately having a negative effect on health. In the UK, these wood pellets come into a number of ports, one of the biggest being Liverpool’s Peel Ports. Communities in this area experience air pollution as a result of this, and Highways England are also planning to destroy the much loved Rimrose Valley to build a road that will increase transportation of wood pellets to Drax’s Power Station in Yorkshire, despite the claim that it will reduce traffic. This is one of several examples of communities that were never given a choice. Would you be willing to use your authority as an MP to change this?
        &lt;ol&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(IF YES)&lt;/strong&gt; Please could you write to Alok Sharma and Kwasi Karteng and ask them to switch biomass subsidies to genuine renewables under the Levy Control Framework, ask Parliamentary Questions about biofuel subsidies, and perhaps request a parliamentary debate around the issue. We can send you &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1DYlkCzT29UNlhdWeM9ceQBJPqPFXlN4Z/view?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;a briefing&lt;/a&gt; on this issue, please could you forward any replies back to my email. Thanks again for listening, have a good day.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(IF NO).&lt;/strong&gt; That’s OK. Thank you for talking to me, have a good day.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;alok-sharma&quot;&gt;Alok Sharma&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;left-message-1&quot;&gt;Left message&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good morning/afternoon. This is _____. I’m reaching out to you to discuss the harmful effect Drax Power Station is having on communities in the UK, in the hopes that you can transfer biomass subsidies to genuine renewables. Please pass on the message to Alok Sharma. If you’d like to hear about this please return my call on [Number] before 5pm today. Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;main-script-1&quot;&gt;Main script&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Good morning/Good afternoon, is Alok Sharma available?
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unless you are very lucky, this will be a resounding no. But it’s fun to ask nonetheless!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hello _______ . This is _______ calling on behalf of the #AxeDrax campaign. I am calling to talk to you about Drax Power Station. Are you aware that Drax Power Station is the greatest emitter of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; in the UK?
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(IF YES)&lt;/strong&gt; - That’s good to know _(Skip to &lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt;) _&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(IF NO)&lt;/strong&gt; - No problem (&lt;strong&gt;Explain about Drax, use the FAQ document&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;That’s good to know that you are aware that the biomass industry isn’t as clean as Drax claims. Would you be willing to hear more about how Drax is harming communities in the UK and USA?
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(IF YES)&lt;/strong&gt; - Great! You might already know that the beginning of Drax’s biomass production is in the Southern USA, where large areas of forests are torn down and pelletised in factories. This process harms the communities because it takes away nature and increases pollution, ultimately having a negative effect on health. In the UK, these wood pellets come into a number of ports, one of the biggest being Liverpool’s Peel Ports. Communities in this area experience air pollution as a result of this, and Highways England are also planning to destroy the much loved Rimrose Valley to build a road that is likely to increase transportation of wood pellets to Drax’s Power Station in Yorkshire, despite the claim that it will reduce traffic. This is one of several examples of communities that were never given a choice. Could you take these issues to Alok Sharma and ask him to move subsidies for biomass to genuine renewables under the Levy Control Framework. &lt;em&gt;(ask for direct email to send details on)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(IF NO)&lt;/strong&gt; - No problem. Thank you for your time and have a good day.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;yeo-valley&quot;&gt;Yeo Valley&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;tel:01761462798&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;01761 462 798&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NB Yeo Valley already get power from Octopus Energy (generally good &amp;amp; not from Drax) as well as Haven Power&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;left-message-2&quot;&gt;Left message&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good morning/afternoon. My name is _____ and I am calling from the Axe Drax campaign.  Could you please get back to me on &lt;em&gt;[Number]&lt;/em&gt; about whether Yeo Valley would consider not sourcing its electricity through Haven Power, and fully switch to a provider that does not pollute communities?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;main-script-2&quot;&gt;Main Script&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Hello _______ . This is _______ calling on behalf of the #AxeDrax campaign. It has come to our attention that Yeo Valley’s energy comes from Haven Power which is owned by Drax. Are you aware that Drax Power Station is the greatest emitter of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; in the UK? \&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(IF NO).&lt;/strong&gt; OK. Although Drax is phasing out coal, their power stations are being converted into biomass plants, with the false claims that this is renewable energy, when in truth it contributes more CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to the atmosphere than coal for the same amount of electricity. Would you be willing to hear more about how Drax is harming communities in the UK and the US?
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(IF NO)&lt;/strong&gt; No problem. I think it is really important that companies like Yeo Valley stop supporting companies like Haven Power, Drax, and Enviva which take part in logging operations in the Southern USA that contribute to air, water and noise pollution in predominantly Black, indigenous and low-income communities - all hidden under lies about renewable energy. Would you be willing to write to me about whether Yeo Valley will continue to support the harmful, polluting biomass industry? &lt;em&gt;(give them your contact details if not hung up yet)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(IF YES)&lt;/strong&gt; Great. You might already know that the beginning of Drax’s biomass production is mostly in the Southern USA, where large areas of forests are torn down and pelletised in factories. This process contributes to air, water and noise pollution that hurts predominantly poorer and non-white communities. In the UK, these wood pellets come into a number of ports, one of the biggest being Liverpool’s Peel Ports. People in the area experience harmful air pollution due to this, and Highways England are also planning to destroy the much loved Rimrose Valley to build a road that is likely to increase transportation of wood pellets to Drax’s Power Station in Yorkshire, despite the claim that it will reduce traffic. This is one of several examples of communities that were never given a choice. Can you see the harm that Drax’s wood burning electricity is causing? &lt;em&gt;(hypothetical, skip straight to 3.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(IF YES)&lt;/strong&gt; As YeoValley is an ethical company that promotes the importance of biodiversity are you going to switch from Haven Power to a genuine renewable energy supplier?
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(IF YES)&lt;/strong&gt; Could you put that in writing to me on [your email]? &lt;em&gt;(forward this to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:axedrax@pm.me&quot;&gt;axedrax@pm.me&lt;/a&gt; if possible)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(IF NO)&lt;/strong&gt; Drax Power Station fuels forest destruction that ultimately will make all of our lives worse. Please could you take my concern to your sustainability lead, and get back to me in writing about your decision?_ (make them take your contact details. Forward any correspondences to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:axedrax@pm.me&quot;&gt;axedrax@pm.me&lt;/a&gt;) _&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;salford-city-council&quot;&gt;Salford City Council&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;tel:01616076987&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0161 607 6987&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;left-message-3&quot;&gt;Left message&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good morning/afternoon. My name is _____ and I am calling from the Axe Drax campaign. Could you please get back to me on &lt;em&gt;[Number]&lt;/em&gt; on whether Salford City Council will follow through on its declaration of a climate emergency and switch from Haven Power to a genuine renewable energy provider?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;main-script-3&quot;&gt;Main script&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Hello _______ . This is _______ calling on behalf of the #AxeDrax campaign. It has come to our attention that Salford City Council’s energy comes from Haven Power which is owned by Drax. Are you aware that Drax Power Station is the greatest emitter of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; in the UK? \&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(IF NO).&lt;/strong&gt; OK. Although Drax is phasing out coal, their power stations are being converted into biomass plants, with the false claims that this is renewable energy, when in truth it contributes more CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to the atmosphere than coal for the same amount of electricity. Would you be willing to hear more about how Drax is harming communities in the UK and the US?
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(IF NO)&lt;/strong&gt; No problem. I think it is really important that councils that have declared a climate emergency should stop supporting companies like Haven Power, Drax, and Enviva which take part in logging operations in the Southern USA that contribute to air, water and noise pollution in predominantly Black, Indigenous and low-income communities - all hidden under lies about renewable energy. Would you be willing to write to me about whether Salford City Council will continue to support the harmful, polluting biomass industry? &lt;em&gt;(give them your contact details if not hung up yet)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(IF YES)&lt;/strong&gt; Great. You might already know that the beginning of Drax’s biomass production is mostly in the Southern USA, where large areas of forests are torn down and pelletised in factories. This process contributes to air, water and noise pollution that hurts predominantly Black, Indigenous and low-income communities. In the UK, these wood pellets come into a number of ports, one of the biggest being Liverpool’s Peel Ports. People in the area experience harmful air pollution due to this, and Highways England are also planning to destroy the much loved Rimrose Valley to build a road that will increase transportation of wood pellets to Drax’s Power Station in Yorkshire, despite the claim that it will reduce traffic. This is one of several examples of communities that were never given a choice. Can you see the harm that Drax’s wood burning electricity is causing? &lt;em&gt;(hypothetical, skip straight to 3)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(IF YES)&lt;/strong&gt; As Salford City Council has declared a climate emergency, are you going to switch from Haven Power to a genuine renewable energy supplier?
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(IF YES)&lt;/strong&gt; Could you put that in writing to me on [your email]? &lt;em&gt;(forward this to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:axedrax@pm.me&quot;&gt;axedrax@pm.me&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;**(IF NO) **Drax Power Station fuels forest destruction that ultimately will make all of our lives worse. Please could you take my concern to your sustainability lead, and get back to me in writing about your decision?_ (make them take your contact details. Forward any correspondences to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:axedrax@pm.me&quot;&gt;axedrax@pm.me&lt;/a&gt;)_
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Worth also emailing them, so they have something to reply to&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;nuances&quot;&gt;Nuances&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Burning wood is less efficient than burning coal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drax imports more wood to burn than the UK produces each year&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drax releases more carbon each year than the UK needs to reduce its emissions by to meet its carbon targets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drax were given £789.5m in 2019 for its wood burning; this can be easily transferred to genuine renewables under the Levy Control Framework&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pellet production produces air, water and noise pollution.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Logging operations in the Southeastern USA make it less protected from inevitable extreme weather events like hurricanes and flooding
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;North Carolina and Robeson County are key area, if you need a specific example&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="action" /><summary type="html">This action was planned a few times through the summer of 2020, this is a summary of the information that was prepared.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/photos/etd_drax.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/photos/etd_drax.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Social Media</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/action/social-media/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Social Media" /><published>2021-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/action/social-media</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/action/social-media/">&lt;p&gt;If you have some time and have accounts, then share information to people on
social media. There are some examples below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;images&quot;&gt;Images&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There should be images in our &lt;a href=&quot;/images&quot;&gt;photo bank&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;examples&quot;&gt;Examples&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tweets&quot;&gt;Tweets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Click on the tweets to share them.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;tweets&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;card&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Drax+Power+Station%E2%80%99s+tree+burning+is+fuelling+%23forest+destruction+%26+the+%23ClimateCrisis.+These+forests+are+pelletised+in+a+process+that+pollutes+water+%26+air%2C+harms+communities%2C+damages+health+%26+makes+the+%23ClimateCrisis+worse%21+It%27s+time+to+%23CutCarbonNotForests.+&quot;&gt;
    &lt;section class=&quot;card tweet&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
        
        
          
          
            Drax
          
        
          
          
            Power
          
        
          
          
            Station’s
          
        
          
          
            tree
          
        
          
          
            burning
          
        
          
          
            is
          
        
          
          
            fuelling
          
        
          
          
            &lt;span class=&quot;hashtag&quot;&gt;#forest&lt;/span&gt;
          
        
          
          
            destruction
          
        
          
          
            &amp;amp;
          
        
          
          
            the
          
        
          
          
            &lt;span class=&quot;hashtag&quot;&gt;#ClimateCrisis.&lt;/span&gt;
          
        
          
          
            These
          
        
          
          
            forests
          
        
          
          
            are
          
        
          
          
            pelletised
          
        
          
          
            in
          
        
          
          
            a
          
        
          
          
            process
          
        
          
          
            that
          
        
          
          
            pollutes
          
        
          
          
            water
          
        
          
          
            &amp;amp;
          
        
          
          
            air,
          
        
          
          
            harms
          
        
          
          
            communities,
          
        
          
          
            damages
          
        
          
          
            health
          
        
          
          
            &amp;amp;
          
        
          
          
            makes
          
        
          
          
            the
          
        
          
          
            &lt;span class=&quot;hashtag&quot;&gt;#ClimateCrisis&lt;/span&gt;
          
        
          
          
            worse!
          
        
          
          
            It's
          
        
          
          
            time
          
        
          
          
            to
          
        
          
          
            &lt;span class=&quot;hashtag&quot;&gt;#CutCarbonNotForests.&lt;/span&gt;
          
        
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/section&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  &lt;a class=&quot;card&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Air+%23pollution+from+Drax+Power+Station+%26+its+logging+operations+harm+local+people%E2%80%99s+health+and+homes.+We+can%27t+be+destroying+our+%23livingplanet+for+a+false+energy+solution.+It+is+time+to+%23AxeDrax+%F0%9F%AA%93+and+fight+for+people+%F0%9F%A7%91%F0%9F%8F%BF%E2%80%8D%F0%9F%A4%9D%E2%80%8D%F0%9F%A7%91%F0%9F%8F%BF+not+profit+%F0%9F%92%B0+%40CCNFUK+&quot;&gt;
    &lt;section class=&quot;card tweet&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
        
        
          
          
            Air
          
        
          
          
            &lt;span class=&quot;hashtag&quot;&gt;#pollution&lt;/span&gt;
          
        
          
          
            from
          
        
          
          
            Drax
          
        
          
          
            Power
          
        
          
          
            Station
          
        
          
          
            &amp;amp;
          
        
          
          
            its
          
        
          
          
            logging
          
        
          
          
            operations
          
        
          
          
            harm
          
        
          
          
            local
          
        
          
          
            people’s
          
        
          
          
            health
          
        
          
          
            and
          
        
          
          
            homes.
          
        
          
          
            We
          
        
          
          
            can't
          
        
          
          
            be
          
        
          
          
            destroying
          
        
          
          
            our
          
        
          
          
            &lt;span class=&quot;hashtag&quot;&gt;#livingplanet&lt;/span&gt;
          
        
          
          
            for
          
        
          
          
            a
          
        
          
          
            false
          
        
          
          
            energy
          
        
          
          
            solution.
          
        
          
          
            It
          
        
          
          
            is
          
        
          
          
            time
          
        
          
          
            to
          
        
          
          
            &lt;span class=&quot;hashtag&quot;&gt;#AxeDrax&lt;/span&gt;
          
        
          
          
            🪓
          
        
          
          
            and
          
        
          
          
            fight
          
        
          
          
            for
          
        
          
          
            people
          
        
          
          
            🧑🏿‍🤝‍🧑🏿
          
        
          
          
            not
          
        
          
          
            profit
          
        
          
          
            💰
          
        
          
          
            &lt;span class=&quot;at&quot;&gt;@CCNFUK&lt;/span&gt;
          
        
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/section&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  &lt;a class=&quot;card&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Drax+Power+Station+relies+on+wood+pellet+factories+for+its+%23dirtyenergy++%F0%9F%8F%AD+Dust+%26+%23pollution+from+this+type+of+facility+have+been+linked+to+respiratory+illness%2C+heart+disease%2C+and+cancer+%F0%9F%98%A8+we+must+%23AxeDrax+%F0%9F%AA%93+before+it+is+too+late.+%23CutCarbonNotForests+&quot;&gt;
    &lt;section class=&quot;card tweet&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
        
        
          
          
            Drax
          
        
          
          
            Power
          
        
          
          
            Station
          
        
          
          
            relies
          
        
          
          
            on
          
        
          
          
            wood
          
        
          
          
            pellet
          
        
          
          
            factories
          
        
          
          
            for
          
        
          
          
            its
          
        
          
          
            &lt;span class=&quot;hashtag&quot;&gt;#dirtyenergy&lt;/span&gt;
          
        
          
          
            🏭
          
        
          
          
            Dust
          
        
          
          
            &amp;amp;
          
        
          
          
            &lt;span class=&quot;hashtag&quot;&gt;#pollution&lt;/span&gt;
          
        
          
          
            from
          
        
          
          
            this
          
        
          
          
            type
          
        
          
          
            of
          
        
          
          
            facility
          
        
          
          
            have
          
        
          
          
            been
          
        
          
          
            linked
          
        
          
          
            to
          
        
          
          
            respiratory
          
        
          
          
            illness,
          
        
          
          
            heart
          
        
          
          
            disease,
          
        
          
          
            and
          
        
          
          
            cancer
          
        
          
          
            😨
          
        
          
          
            we
          
        
          
          
            must
          
        
          
          
            &lt;span class=&quot;hashtag&quot;&gt;#AxeDrax&lt;/span&gt;
          
        
          
          
            🪓
          
        
          
          
            before
          
        
          
          
            it
          
        
          
          
            is
          
        
          
          
            too
          
        
          
          
            late.
          
        
          
          
            &lt;span class=&quot;hashtag&quot;&gt;#CutCarbonNotForests&lt;/span&gt;
          
        
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/section&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  &lt;a class=&quot;card&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Drax+Power+Station%E2%80%99s+tree+burning+is+devastating+communities+%26+the+%23climate.+We+must+fight+for+the+people+affected+by+logging+%26+dirty+pellet+mills+in+The+US+and+%23AxeDrax+%F0%9F%AA%93+in+the+UK.+End+the+demand%2C+end+the+destruction.+We+must+act+now+to+%23CutCarbonNotForests+&quot;&gt;
    &lt;section class=&quot;card tweet&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
        
        
          
          
            Drax
          
        
          
          
            Power
          
        
          
          
            Station’s
          
        
          
          
            tree
          
        
          
          
            burning
          
        
          
          
            is
          
        
          
          
            devastating
          
        
          
          
            communities
          
        
          
          
            &amp;amp;
          
        
          
          
            the
          
        
          
          
            &lt;span class=&quot;hashtag&quot;&gt;#climate.&lt;/span&gt;
          
        
          
          
            We
          
        
          
          
            must
          
        
          
          
            fight
          
        
          
          
            for
          
        
          
          
            the
          
        
          
          
            people
          
        
          
          
            affected
          
        
          
          
            by
          
        
          
          
            logging
          
        
          
          
            &amp;amp;
          
        
          
          
            dirty
          
        
          
          
            pellet
          
        
          
          
            mills
          
        
          
          
            in
          
        
          
          
            The
          
        
          
          
            US
          
        
          
          
            and
          
        
          
          
            &lt;span class=&quot;hashtag&quot;&gt;#AxeDrax&lt;/span&gt;
          
        
          
          
            🪓
          
        
          
          
            in
          
        
          
          
            the
          
        
          
          
            UK.
          
        
          
          
            End
          
        
          
          
            the
          
        
          
          
            demand,
          
        
          
          
            end
          
        
          
          
            the
          
        
          
          
            destruction.
          
        
          
          
            We
          
        
          
          
            must
          
        
          
          
            act
          
        
          
          
            now
          
        
          
          
            to
          
        
          
          
            &lt;span class=&quot;hashtag&quot;&gt;#CutCarbonNotForests&lt;/span&gt;
          
        
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/section&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  &lt;a class=&quot;card&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Drax+Power+Station+is+the+world%E2%80%99s+largest+%23tree+burner.+This+false+solution+destroys+forests%2C+harms+wildlife%2C+adds+to+the+%23ClimateCrisis+%26+pollutes+communities+who+are+already+suffering+from+poverty+%26+injustice.+We+must+%23CutCarbonNotForests+%26+%23AxeDrax+%F0%9F%AA%93+&quot;&gt;
    &lt;section class=&quot;card tweet&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
        
        
          
          
            Drax
          
        
          
          
            Power
          
        
          
          
            Station
          
        
          
          
            is
          
        
          
          
            the
          
        
          
          
            world’s
          
        
          
          
            largest
          
        
          
          
            &lt;span class=&quot;hashtag&quot;&gt;#tree&lt;/span&gt;
          
        
          
          
            burner.
          
        
          
          
            This
          
        
          
          
            false
          
        
          
          
            solution
          
        
          
          
            destroys
          
        
          
          
            forests,
          
        
          
          
            harms
          
        
          
          
            wildlife,
          
        
          
          
            adds
          
        
          
          
            to
          
        
          
          
            the
          
        
          
          
            &lt;span class=&quot;hashtag&quot;&gt;#ClimateCrisis&lt;/span&gt;
          
        
          
          
            &amp;amp;
          
        
          
          
            pollutes
          
        
          
          
            communities
          
        
          
          
            who
          
        
          
          
            are
          
        
          
          
            already
          
        
          
          
            suffering
          
        
          
          
            from
          
        
          
          
            poverty
          
        
          
          
            &amp;amp;
          
        
          
          
            injustice.
          
        
          
          
            We
          
        
          
          
            must
          
        
          
          
            &lt;span class=&quot;hashtag&quot;&gt;#CutCarbonNotForests&lt;/span&gt;
          
        
          
          
            &amp;amp;
          
        
          
          
            &lt;span class=&quot;hashtag&quot;&gt;#AxeDrax&lt;/span&gt;
          
        
          
          
            🪓
          
        
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/section&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  &lt;a class=&quot;card&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Dear+%5B%40myMP%5D%2C+for+the+sake+of+people+%26+planet%2C+please+ensure+that+UK+renewable+subsidies+are+no+longer+used+to+fund+%23biomass+power+stations+which+burn+%23trees%2C+pollute+communities+%26+harm+the+planet%27s+health.+Send+a+letter+to+%40AlokSharma_RDG+now.+%23CutCarbonNotForests&quot;&gt;
    &lt;section class=&quot;card tweet&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
        
        
          
          
            Dear
          
        
          
          
            [@myMP],
          
        
          
          
            for
          
        
          
          
            the
          
        
          
          
            sake
          
        
          
          
            of
          
        
          
          
            people
          
        
          
          
            &amp;amp;
          
        
          
          
            planet,
          
        
          
          
            please
          
        
          
          
            ensure
          
        
          
          
            that
          
        
          
          
            UK
          
        
          
          
            renewable
          
        
          
          
            subsidies
          
        
          
          
            are
          
        
          
          
            no
          
        
          
          
            longer
          
        
          
          
            used
          
        
          
          
            to
          
        
          
          
            fund
          
        
          
          
            &lt;span class=&quot;hashtag&quot;&gt;#biomass&lt;/span&gt;
          
        
          
          
            power
          
        
          
          
            stations
          
        
          
          
            which
          
        
          
          
            burn
          
        
          
          
            &lt;span class=&quot;hashtag&quot;&gt;#trees,&lt;/span&gt;
          
        
          
          
            pollute
          
        
          
          
            communities
          
        
          
          
            &amp;amp;
          
        
          
          
            harm
          
        
          
          
            the
          
        
          
          
            planet's
          
        
          
          
            health.
          
        
          
          
            Send
          
        
          
          
            a
          
        
          
          
            letter
          
        
          
          
            to
          
        
          
          
            &lt;span class=&quot;at&quot;&gt;@AlokSharma_RDG&lt;/span&gt;
          
        
          
          
            now.
          
        
          
          
            &lt;span class=&quot;hashtag&quot;&gt;#CutCarbonNotForests&lt;/span&gt;
          
        
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/section&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

  &lt;a class=&quot;card&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=Dear+%5B%40myMP%5D%2C+Drax+Power+Station+receives+%C2%A32.1m+a+day+in+UK+renewable+subsidies+to+burn+%23trees.+Call+on+%40KwasiKwarteng+%26+%40AlokSharma_RDG+to+transfer+these+subsidies+to+renewables%2C+%23AxeDrax+%F0%9F%AA%93+and+protect+the+communities+directly+harmed+by+dirty+energy+%23CutCarbonNotForests&quot;&gt;
    &lt;section class=&quot;card tweet&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;
        
        
          
          
            Dear
          
        
          
          
            [@myMP],
          
        
          
          
            Drax
          
        
          
          
            Power
          
        
          
          
            Station
          
        
          
          
            receives
          
        
          
          
            £2.1m
          
        
          
          
            a
          
        
          
          
            day
          
        
          
          
            in
          
        
          
          
            UK
          
        
          
          
            renewable
          
        
          
          
            subsidies
          
        
          
          
            to
          
        
          
          
            burn
          
        
          
          
            &lt;span class=&quot;hashtag&quot;&gt;#trees.&lt;/span&gt;
          
        
          
          
            Call
          
        
          
          
            on
          
        
          
          
            &lt;span class=&quot;at&quot;&gt;@KwasiKwarteng&lt;/span&gt;
          
        
          
          
            &amp;amp;
          
        
          
          
            &lt;span class=&quot;at&quot;&gt;@AlokSharma_RDG&lt;/span&gt;
          
        
          
          
            to
          
        
          
          
            transfer
          
        
          
          
            these
          
        
          
          
            subsidies
          
        
          
          
            to
          
        
          
          
            renewables,
          
        
          
          
            &lt;span class=&quot;hashtag&quot;&gt;#AxeDrax&lt;/span&gt;
          
        
          
          
            🪓
          
        
          
          
            and
          
        
          
          
            protect
          
        
          
          
            the
          
        
          
          
            communities
          
        
          
          
            directly
          
        
          
          
            harmed
          
        
          
          
            by
          
        
          
          
            dirty
          
        
          
          
            energy
          
        
          
          
            &lt;span class=&quot;hashtag&quot;&gt;#CutCarbonNotForests&lt;/span&gt;
          
        
      &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/section&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;facebook&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out one of the images from &lt;a href=&quot;/images&quot;&gt;our photo bank&lt;/a&gt;, take your own,
or even record a short video. Then make sure to add a caption to educate people!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some example posts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;facebook&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;While many of us have been enjoying the respite of some clean air, those living near Drax Power Station in the UK and near its pellet supplies factories in the USA have not had the same break.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Drax continues to pollute communities and increase the chance of heart disease, respiratory illness and cancer. For the sake of people’s live, it is time to #AxeDrax and move the ridiculous £789.5 million of “renewable energy” subsidies which Drax received in 2019 to genuine renewables that don’t harm communities and provide secure green jobs.  #CutCarbonNotForests&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Take action: https://www.axedrax.ga/action &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Find out more from The Dogwood Alliance here: https://www.dogwoodalliance.org/2019/10/alabama-groups-oppose-envivas-epes-facility/ &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
And from Biofuelwatch:&lt;br /&gt;
https://www.biofuelwatch.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/drax-info-sheet_1-compressed.pdf &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;br /&gt;
Take action: https://actionnetwork.org/forms/axe-drax &lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/section&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;facebook&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&quot;When I heard about Enviva coming to Richmond County, it felt like my heart dropped in my stomach. Nobody educated our little town here - not on the Perdue Chicken Plant, on the CSX railway, or on the Enviva wood pellet plant.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&quot;My hope for my community is that we all join together and fight together and win the biomass challenge. Winning would make me feel so good. It would allow me to be able to go to another community and help them. We won't stop when we win - we will keep going.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;
Debra David&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Source: https://www.dogwoodalliance.org &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/photos/dogwoodalliance.org/debra_david.png&quot; alt=&quot;Example post image&quot; /&gt;
    
  &lt;/section&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="action" /><summary type="html">If you have some time and have accounts, then share information to people on social media. There are some examples below.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/photos/etd_drax.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/photos/etd_drax.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Join Zoom calls</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/action/zoom/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Join Zoom calls" /><published>2021-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/action/zoom</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/action/zoom/">&lt;p&gt;Especially while many things are online, Drax will be running a lot
of talks about how great they are 🙄. This is our chance to pop in and
ask a few questions they might not have been expecting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We aren’t going to persuade any of Drax employees (unless you’re really good!),
but hopefully it will help others cut through Drax’s relentless “Greenwashing”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to&quot;&gt;How to&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Find the link to the call. Hopefully there will be one on our
&lt;a href=&quot;/events&quot;&gt;events page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Join it and look interested&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask questions and provide links to resources for others in the call
to learn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-questions&quot;&gt;The questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a few compiled questions, please email us with more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tree-burning&quot;&gt;Tree burning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is it normal for Green Energy suppliers to be given &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-york-north-yorkshire-56130166&quot;&gt;$2.5 millon fines&lt;/a&gt; for
air pollution violations?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do all “green projects” actively &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.greenbiz.com/article/europes-wood-pellet-market-worsening-environmental-racism-american-south&quot;&gt;worsen environmental racism&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The biomass industry admits it will &lt;a href=&quot;https://forestdefenders.eu/we-cant-wait-100-years-for-trees-to-grow-back-we-need-to-reduce-emissions-now/&quot;&gt;take 100 years for carbon neutrality&lt;/a&gt;.
Why are Drax lying about this?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pellet-production&quot;&gt;Pellet production&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wood pellet production has been described as so polluting that it “leaves people prisoners in their own homes”. Why don’t we use real renewable energy?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;beccs&quot;&gt;BECCS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why is Drax not going ahead with your BECCS partnership with C-Capture? Was the partnership unsuccessful?&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.desmog.co.uk/2019/07/17/comment-policymakers-shouldn-t-trust-drax-s-bizarre-tree-burning-climate-solution&quot;&gt;More info about C-Capture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If the carbon capture technology is added to the biomass units, what is the energy penalty and how much additional biomass will need to be burned for the same electricity output that Drax Power Station currently generates?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If the amount of wood burned at Drax doesn’t increase, how much less electricity will be generated? And what trials specific to the technology chosen are Drax’s BECCS assumptions based on?&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If BECCS technology were ever made to work in the future, it would mean an increased demand for wood to supply enough energy to capture and store the CO2. This would lead to more forest destruction and the conversion of huge areas of land to monoculture tree plantations in order to supply wood to burn in power stations &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scotsman.com/news/opinion/burning-trees-will-not-save-us-climate-crisis-richard-dixon-3112293&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;For more information, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foei.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Friends-of-the-Earth-International_BECCS_English.pdf&quot;&gt;please see page 2 of this report from Friends of the Earth International&lt;/a&gt;: “ Providing enough biomass for BECCS, at the scale needed, would only be possible through deforestation, land-grabbing, and by converting large amounts of arable land into monoculture plantations. This means that BECCS will create competition for land among food producers, as more and more cropland will be dedicated to growing crops for fuel. In fact, it is estimated that rolling out BECCS at scale will require up to 3000 million hectares – around twice the amount of land that is currently already cultivated, globally.”&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How much CO2 has Drax captured and stored so far in each of your two pilot projects and over what time period?&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Drax plans to capture 1 tonne of CO2 per day but as yet, has released all of it back into the atmosphere. For more information, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biofuelwatch.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/drax-briefing-update-2020_compressed.pdf&quot;&gt;please see page 6 of this Drax briefing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;further-articles-for-your-information&quot;&gt;Further articles, for your information&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;policymakers-shouldnt-trust-draxs-bizarre-tree-burning-climate-solution---almuth-ernsting-2272019&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drax.com/sustainability/environment/&quot;&gt;Policymakers Shouldn’t Trust Drax’s Bizarre Tree-Burning Climate Solution - Almuth Ernsting (22/7/2019)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Drax brazenly claims that it has “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drax.com/sustainability/environment/&quot;&gt;a significant role to play in the transition to a low-carbon future&lt;/a&gt;” – without alluding to the fact that closing down its power plant would cut the UK’s carbon dioxide emissions by over 17 million tonnes a year. Last year, Drax announced that it wanted to go further and turn its plant into the “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drax.com/press_release/europes-first-bioenergy-carbon-capture-storage-pilot-now-underway/&quot;&gt;first carbon negative power station&lt;/a&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It entered into a partnership with startup company, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c-capture.co.uk/&quot;&gt;C-Capture&lt;/a&gt;, to try and capture one tonne of carbon dioxide daily. This carbon dioxide was to be sold to pubs to “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drax.com/press_release/drax-help-keep-fizz-drinks-sector/&quot;&gt;help keep the fizz&lt;/a&gt;” in beer.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.power-technology.com/features/draxs-carbon-capture/&quot;&gt;As of May&lt;/a&gt;, the process was not working reliably, and no carbon dioxide was stored or sold. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biofuelwatch.org.uk/2019/beccs-pilot-farce/&quot;&gt;This is not surprising&lt;/a&gt;: C-Capture, though founded in 2009, had participated in no previous projects, obtained no patents and published no scientific studies. Instead of using a tried-and-tested solvent for capturing carbon, it chose to make its own, without disclosing any details. […]&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The inclusion of BECCS into climate policies is dangerous: because BECCS is unlikely to work and, if it did, likely to result in extra carbon dioxide emissions from increased logging and land conversion.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;burning-trees-will-not-save-us-from-the-climate-crisis---richard-dixon-26121&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scotsman.com/news/opinion/burning-trees-will-not-save-us-climate-crisis-richard-dixon-3112293&quot;&gt;Burning trees will not save us from the climate crisis - Richard Dixon (26/1/21)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The new report shows how &lt;strong&gt;BECCS is being used as a get out of jail card by governments and companies to do little about climate change but tell us all it’s going to be alright&lt;/strong&gt;. BECCS is popular because countries around the world looked at their expected emissions, saw the widening gap between the trajectory they are on and the targets they are supposed to meet, and simply plugged in the magic unicorn of BECCS to fill the gap.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[…] There is no fully-functioning BECCS scheme operating anywhere in the world.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Of course, planting trees can be a great thing to do but &lt;strong&gt;to make BECCS work at scale you need a huge amount of plant material or timber. This would only be possible by destroying natural forests and converting large areas of arable land into monoculture plantations, displacing people, trashing nature and competing with food production.&lt;/strong&gt; One estimate is that we would need twice as much land as is currently cultivated on a global scale and, according to an assessment in 2019, BECCS at massive scale would threaten an additional 150 million people with hunger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;letter-regarding-use-of-forests-for-bioenergy-1122021&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dropbox.com/s/hdmmcnd0d1d2lq5/Scientist%20Letter%20to%20Biden%2C%20von%20der%20Leyen%2C%20Michel%2C%20Suga%20%26%20Moon%20%20Re.%20Forest%20Biomass%20%28February%2011%2C%202021%29.pdf?dl=0&quot;&gt;Letter Regarding Use of Forests for Bioenergy, 11/2/2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And some related press releases:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ecowatch.com/scientists-demand-stop-burning-trees-2650534163.html&quot;&gt;500+ Scientists Demand Stop to Tree Burning as Climate Solution&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wwf.eu/?uNewsID=2128466&quot;&gt;From WWF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In recent years, however, there has been a misguided move to cut down whole trees or to divert large portions of stem wood for bioenergy, releasing carbon that would otherwise stay locked up in forests.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The result of this additional wood harvest is a large initial increase in carbon emissions, creating a “carbon debt,” which increases over time as more trees are harvested for continuing bioenergy use. &lt;strong&gt;Regrowing trees and displacement of fossil fuels may eventually pay off this carbon debt, but regrowth takes time the world does not have to solve climate change.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As numerous studies have shown, this burning of wood will increase warming for decades to centuries. That is true even when the wood replaces coal, oil or natural gas. […]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To avoid these harms, governments must end subsidies and other incentives that today exist for the burning of wood whether from their forests or others. The European Union needs to stop treating the burning of biomass as carbon neutral in its renewable energy standards and in its emissions trading system.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;global-markets-for-biomass-energy-are-devastating-us-forests-2019&quot;&gt;“Global Markets for Biomass Energy are Devastating US Forests” (2019)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dogwoodalliance.org/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/Biomass-Investigation-Booklet-2019.pdf&quot;&gt;Investigation booklet into the sourcing of wood biomass from Southern US forests&lt;/a&gt; by the world’s largest wood pellet producer, Enviva. This wood is being transported from the Southern US to burn in UK &amp;amp; European power stations, including Drax&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Despite the claims of the industry, the independent reporting shows a disturbing pattern: wood pellets burned by Drax and others come from wood that is harvested from native hardwood forests in an area designated as a global biodiversity hotspot.&lt;/strong&gt; They also spotlight the vast quantities of whole trees and other large-diameter wood— biomass feedstocks known to be high-carbon—that are entering Enviva’s supply chain.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;**Not only is this devastating for these irreplaceable forests, but it’s worsening our Earth’s climate crisis. Multiple independent, peer-reviewed studies have determined that burning biomass from forests for electricity creates more carbon dioxide emissions than burning coal, and that increased carbon dioxide concentrations persist in the atmosphere for decades or more””&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In March 2019, investigators in North Carolina again tracked logging trucks from a mature hardwood forest to Enviva’s Northampton wood pellet mill. In January 2018, reporters from the UK Channel 4 News program Dispatches traveled to North Carolina to examine what is happening on the ground in the forests that have become ground zero for feeding Drax Power Station’s voracious demand for wood. &lt;strong&gt;The images from the Dispatches investigation tell a story of ecological devastation in the name of clean energy: a once majestic wetland forest clearcut to supply wood to Enviva, and ultimately to Drax.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="action" /><summary type="html">Especially while many things are online, Drax will be running a lot of talks about how great they are 🙄. This is our chance to pop in and ask a few questions they might not have been expecting.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/photos/etd_drax.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/photos/etd_drax.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Drax Expand Logging into Canadian Woodland for £436m deal</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/press/pinnicle-pellets/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Drax Expand Logging into Canadian Woodland for £436m deal" /><published>2021-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/press/pinnicle-pellets</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/press/pinnicle-pellets/">&lt;p&gt;Drax Plc plan to buy further into the wood burning industry, by purchasing
Pinnacle “Renewable Energy”. This company log some of the last remaining old
forests in British Columbia, to be burned at Drax Power Station in
North Yorkshire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They will be voting on this a the end of March, and remote votes must be in by
29th March. This is a surprise as Drax plan to have their Annual General
meeting on 21st April.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stand.earth/latest/forest-conservation/forests-and-wood-pellets/drax-dont-burn-canada%E2%80%99s-old-growth-forests&quot;&gt;this summary article&lt;/a&gt; by Canadian organisation Stand.Earth. Stand.Earth
have also launched a full investigation into British Columbia’s which can be read
in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stand.earth/sites/stand/files/report-canada-wood-pellet-industry.pdf&quot;&gt;this document&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a quote taken from the above article:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;UK residents may be shocked to learn that their power is being generated
  by burning some of the last stands of old and natural forests in British
  Columbia, home to endangered wildlife like caribou and among the most
  carbon-rich in the world—right up until they are clearcut to make wood
  pellets.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In no world is this acceptable, and to be growing this sector during a
  global climate crisis is horrifying. Old growth forests in BC are nearly
  gone, and the provincial government campaigned on a commitment to protect
  old forests while pursuing a paradigm shift for forestry. We were promised
  a new future for forests, but allowing them instead to be clearcut and
  shipped overseas to be burned in coal converted plants is medieval.
  People living in the UK and Canada must come together to oppose this
  industry and support real, clean renewable energy that protects forests
  and our climate.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tegan Hansen, Forest Campaigner, Stand.earth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &lt;strong&gt;cannot go unanswered in the UK&lt;/strong&gt;, and we must take the short time
we have to do everything we can to stop Drax committing this climate
crime. We must remember that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biofuelwatch.org.uk/axedrax-campaign/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;the UK Government fund Drax&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and that
any crime Drax commit the Government are complicit in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We must come together and take action. Watch this space for suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Areas we need help in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Managing our social media&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Writing press releases&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Affinity groups prepared to take action independently&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People who can make info-graphics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact us on &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:axedrax@pm.me&quot;&gt;axedrax [at] pm.me&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to
get involved in organising against Drax. Any amount of help is appreciated. You
also just &lt;a href=&quot;https://axedrax.ga/signup/&quot;&gt;sign up&lt;/a&gt; for updates about taking action.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="press" /><summary type="html">On 31st March, Drax shareholders will vote on acquiring the wood pellet production company Pinnacle Pellets. This will mean ancient forests burned in UK power station.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/photos/viewsfromabove/viewsfromabove.jpeg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/photos/viewsfromabove/viewsfromabove.jpeg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">End the Train of Destruction</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/press/etd/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="End the Train of Destruction" /><published>2020-08-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-08-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/press/etd</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/press/etd/">&lt;p&gt;
  The Axe Drax group, a coalition between Biofuelwatch, Extinction
  Rebellion and Save Rimrose Valley are taking action on the 14th
  of August against Drax Power Station, the UK’s biggest polluter.
  Campaigners will stage creative and peaceful protests at 11 locations
  along the Drax train line which transports wood pellets from Liverpool
  Port to Drax Power Station. Alongside this there will be digital and
  social media actions. These actions are calling for an end to Drax’s
  tree burning and its train of destruction that carves a path through
  the North. Actions will range from banner drops to family-friendly
  puppet shows and tree planting. Campaigners will also call on MPs
  to transfer around £1 billion in UK renewable subsidies from biomass
  burning power stations like Drax to genuine renewables.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The Axe Drax protestors have three demands:
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Stop Subsidising Ecocide: the government must remove the
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biofuelwatch.org.uk/axedrax-campaign/#C3&quot;&gt;
        £789.5 million in subsidies
      &lt;/a&gt;
      for Drax Power Station and transfer
      them to genuine renewables.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Leave it in the Ground: stop Drax building Europe’s biggest ever
      fossil gas power station.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Stop the Lies: end what is possibly the most comprehensive and
      dangerous greenwashing campaign the UK has seen.
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Twelve times a day the Drax trains cross the viaduct in the centre of our
    little West Yorkshire town of Todmorden. They're really long, usually 25
    wagons,  and they really do draw your eye. The slogans on all the wagons
    look really progressive 'Biofuels-powering the future’ and 'Pioneering the
    northern powerhouse'. It’s only because I campaigned in the past over Drax's
    coal burning emissions that I decided to investigate their claims for myself.
    I found out they were greenwashing these claims and were not only causing
    massive environmental damage but huge social harm too.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Maggie Smith from Todmorden&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Drax Power Station, located in Yorkshire, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biofuelwatch.org.uk/axedrax-campaign/#easy-footnote-1-9267&quot;&gt;
    burns 12 million tonnes of trees
    every year
  &lt;/a&gt;. Despite being legally classified as ‘renewable’
  by the UK government, it remains the largest carbon emitter in the
  UK. This takes advantage of a carbon accounting loophole,
  meaning that they are able to exclude the carbon cost of clear
  felling forests in the US when they are burned in the UK. In 2019
  Drax emitted almost 13 million tonnes of CO₂ from burning wood, and
  received £2.36 million in daily subsidy with £2.16 million counted
  as renewable subsidies. This is a grave misuse of public money,
  and Axe Drax are calling for an end to all subsidies for Drax and for
  them to be transferred towards funding genuine renewable energy projects.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  We are taking action, not only because of the environmental damage
  caused but the immediate and destructive impact Drax has upon human
  lives. Supposed bioenergy solutions often have the same fatal flaws
  associated with fossil fuels, they hurt low income BIPOC communities the
  most and serve to perpetuate environmental racism.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  In the Southern US, communities living in close proximity to the
  wood pellet mills used to supply Drax suffer from
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dogwoodalliance.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Community-Voices-Fact-Sheet.pdf&quot;&gt;
  air, water and noise pollution
  &lt;/a&gt; as well as
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dogwoodalliance.org/2020/06/the-injustice-of-bioenergy-production/&quot;&gt;
  poverty and injustice
  &lt;/a&gt;. The
  destruction of forests caused by Drax also destroys
  biodiverse forests which local communities depend on for
  clean air and water. These forests have historically
  served to protect communities from extreme weather and flooding:
  only set to increase in the near future due to climate breakdown.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;https://www.dogwoodalliance.org/2020/06/the-injustice-of-bioenergy-production/&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    Enviva has made people prisoners in their own homes. People are
    profiting and we’re suffering.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Belinda Joyner, Dogwood Alliance Campaigner&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Harm brought upon communities by Drax occurs closer to home too,
  following the train line of destruction through the North.
  The extreme amount of wood pellets imported through Liverpool
  Peel Ports by Drax has forced the port to expand. This has created
  large amounts of noise pollution and disruption upon local communities -
  all so that Drax can continue slashing down ancient woodlands and pumping
  pollution into our air. Noise pollution follows the train line, harming
  communities in Calderdale all the way along to Selby which suffers from
  the constant pumping of pollution into the air.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Despite their constant greenwashing Drax continues to demonstrate a
  complete disregard for people's health, let alone the planet.
  In Selby, local air pollution levels are not measured - making it
  impossible for us to know exactly how much Drax is harming the health
  of local communities - despite the fact that York and the surrounding
  area have robust measuring systems in place. We know that
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pfpi.net/air-pollution-2&quot;&gt;burning wood
  pellets emits a large amount of air pollution&lt;/a&gt;, yet Drax fails to take
  responsibility for this.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    The practice of chopping down healthy trees to make pellets
    in the USA and importing these to the UK to be burned is just
    about as unsustainable as it gets.  Sadly, the Port of Liverpool
    is facilitating this.  With no hint of irony its owners, Peel
    Ports, bemoan the absence of East-West rail links for the
    movement of freight, but are more than happy to occupy a
    vital East-West link specifically for Drax, which could
    and should be being used to move containers.  Instead,
    Peel Ports are sitting back and waiting for the
    Government to build them a road for their HGVs, through a
    vital country park, destroying more trees in the process.
    This is what we're fighting and it's one of the reasons the
    Save Rimrose Valley campaign supports the calls Axe Drax.
    Big business literally bulldoze their way through our green
    spaces, harming the environment and impacting people's lives.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;It has to stop.&lt;/strong&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;cite&gt;Ms Kate Elder Fuller, Save Rimrose Valley campaigner&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  The push for biofuels as a renewable solution is only increasing as we
  hurt towards climate and ecological collapse. AxeDrax has come together
  to demand that we listen to the science which demonstrates biofuels are
  not a viable solution. We demand that our government invests money in
  genuine renewables, that prioritise the well-being of communities and our
  planet over profit.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Notes for editors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biofuelwatch.org.uk/wp-content/uploads/drax-briefing-update-2020_compressed.pdf&quot;&gt;
      Biofuelwatch’s briefing on Drax
    &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dogwoodalliance.org/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Community-Voices-Fact-Sheet.pdf&quot;&gt;
      Dogwood Alliance - Community Voices Fact Sheet
    &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dogwoodalliance.org/2020/06/the-injustice-of-bioenergy-production/&quot;&gt;
      The Injustice of Bioenergy Production
    &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pfpi.net/air-pollution-2&quot;&gt;
      Biomass and air pollution
    &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.biofuelwatch.org.uk/axedrax-campaign/#C3&quot;&gt;
      Drax subsidies
    &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Coronavirus&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Though we must take action, we must do so safely. Each of those taking
  action in person will be maintaining social distancing as far as
  possible, and will be wearing PPE with hand sanitizer available.
  We have provided safety guidelines to each group taking part in this
  action about following public health advice - as with climate change
  we aim to listen to the experts.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  We feel a duty to to balance the needs of people’s safety with the
  necessity of holding Drax accountable due to their greenwashing and
  ecologically destructive behaviour that destroys forests and livelihoods
  here in the North and in America. We are constantly making these decisions,
  and all are able to be changed if the situation regarding COVID-19 changes.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="press" /><summary type="html">Climate campaigners will take part in peaceful and creative actions along the Liverpool-Selby train line to denounce the UKs biggest carbon emitter, Drax Power Station</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/photos/etd_drax.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/photos/etd_drax.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>